Mary Donovan Martello

Omaha, NE

Profile

I was a lawyer and a CPA for 25 years, but I have been studying computer programming and data science since May of 2018 and I am now seeking employment in the data science industry. I will earn a Masters in Data Science through Bellevue University in June of 2021, and I also have completed a COBOL class through AIM Code School (f/k/a Interface, the Web School) and a front-end web development class through the Midland University Code Academy. I also volunteer as a teaching assistant for Mystery Code Society.

Highlighted skills and knowledge include:

- Python and R
- Data mining
- Predictive analytics
- Data wrangling and exploration
- Deep learning
- Data Visualization
- Statistics
- COBOL
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript

- Accounting/financial/ tax analysis
- Writing and speaking skills
- Research a
- Excel spreadsheets

Experience

Self-Employed – Estate and Business Planning Attorney

- Negotiate with taxing authorities
- Conduct trust accounting and reformation proceedings
- Analyze and reconcile entity accountings and reports
- Design complex estate and business plans
- Administer estates and trusts

February 2017 - Present

Dvorak & Donovan Law Group, LLC Attorney – Estate and Business Planning

Founding Member and Equity Partner

Equity Partner/Associate Attorney

- Managed financial and business aspects of the firm
- Led estate planning and administration practice
- Designed complex estate and business plans
- Trained and developed attorneys

Koley Jessen, P.C. L.L.O. Attorney – Estate and Business Planning

• Same duties as listed in above legal jobs

January 2015 – February 2017

August 1999 - January 2015

Resume: Mary Donovan Martello

Nelson, Morrow & Waldron Law Office Attorney – Estate and Business Planning

March 1998 - August 1999

• Same duties as listed in above legal jobs

Coopers & Lybrand L.L.P. (National Accounting Firm) September 1995 – April 1998 Certified Public Accountant

- Obtained a Certified Public Accountant license
- Researched and planned for corporate, partnership and individual taxation issues
- Researched business and estate planning issues
- Drafted correspondence to the Internal Revenue Service and state departments of revenue
- Prepared and reviewed tax returns

Education

Bellevue University, Bellevue, Nebraska Masters in Data Science Candidate Business Analytics Certificate

Nov 2019 - Present Nov 2018 - Feb

2019

Python, R Programming, EDA, Data Mining, Predictive Analytics

AIM Institute/Interface: The Web School, Omaha, Nebraska Interface COBOL Course

Sept – Dec 2018

COBOL

Midland University Code Academy, Omaha, Nebraska Web Foundations

May – August 2018

Wed Foundations

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript

Creighton University School of Law, Omaha, Nebraska Juris Doctor

Emphasis on tax and estate planning courses

May 1995 Magna Cum Laude Class rank: 9/155

Creighton University – College of Business, Omaha, Nebraska Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Business/Law Accelerated Program – Emphasis on accounting courses

May 1993 Summa Cum Laude GPA: 4.0

Volunteer Activity

- Mystery Code Society (Teaching Assistant)
- Omaha Morning Rotary (President /Treasurer)
- Coalition on Human Trafficking
- Omaha Estate Planning Council
- Former TeamMates Mentor